register123.com 2014-06-25

# Certain Inc :: Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy for Certain, Inc.  
**This Privacy Policy applies to [www.certain.com](http://www.certain.com/) owned and operated by Certain, Inc. Certain, Inc. (“Certain”) is committed to respecting your online privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of any Personally Identifiable Information you share with us. Certain has established this Privacy Policy so that you can understand how we use and protect your Personally Identifiable Information.  The array of compliance needs and standards seems to be in a state of constant change and can be daunting.  Certain provides our customers enhanced peace of mind for many different privacy and protection laws including PCI, HIPAA, DSS, PII, SOX, SAS 70, OWASP, as well as U.S., Swiss, and  E.U. Safe Harbor Frameworks.

Certain, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiable information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@certain.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site www.certain.com, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site.

This Privacy Policy relates to the website: [www.certain.com](http://www.certain.com/) and services provided through Certain Website or Certain-Powered Websites. A “Certain-Powered Website” shall mean a domain not owned by Certain, but which has a license from Certain to utilize specific Certain technologies. A “User” means any individual who has access to or uses a Certain Website or Certain-Powered Website, including buyers of Certain software services, attendees of meetings organized through a Certain Website or Certain-Powered Website, visitors to Public Websites, and other employees and agents of corporate clients and Suppliers.

We cover only our data processing practices described in this Privacy Policy. Without limitation, this Privacy Policy does not cover data that we collect offline, on businesses or legal entities or on our employees.

**Notice and Disclosure  
**Personally Identifiable Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual User, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, a home or other physical address, an e-mail address or other contact information. In general, you can visit Certain’s’ web pages without telling us who you are or revealing any Personally Identifiable Information about yourself.

**Information Collection and Use**

When you request a demo or decide to download a buyers guide, we will collect personally identifiable information from you, such as, but not limited to your name, email address and phone number. We will use this information to fulfill your order, send you the requested product or service information or respond to customer service requests.

Third parties provide certain services on Certain’s’ behalf. For example, Certain contracts with third parties to process payment information. Certain may provide information, including Personally Identifiable Information that Certain collects, to such third party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information and services. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information  _only as necessary to provide  _these services to us. These third party service providers are obligated to protect your Personally Identifiable Information on Certain’s’ behalf, and to comply with this Privacy Policy.

If you decide to use Certain software services, we will collect registration information for events. After completing registration, your information is transferred to the event organizer and becomes the responsibility of the meeting planner and event organizer. The registration data that we collect is the property of the contracted organization at all times. Certain is not responsible for the privacy practices of meeting planners and event organizers who are our clients. End users submitting personally identifiable information to client users of Certain software are subject to the sharing, updating, and use restrictions and rights of the individual client.

**Suppliers of Services to Corporate Clients  
**Certain provides access to its applications via Certain Websites and/or Certain-Powered Websites to suppliers of services to corporate clients. Such entities would include hotels, convention and visitors bureaus, and destination management companies.

**Buyers of Services for Corporate Clients  
**Individuals and companies (“Buyers”) use Certains’ technology via the Certain Website or Certain-Powered Websites on behalf of corporate clients to manage meetings, and to purchase services for these meetings and events from Suppliers.

**Attendees of Meetings Planned by Corporate Clients  
**Attendees use Certain software services when invited by a corporate client to attend a meeting. They do so by viewing a Certain-Powered Website that contains questions created by the corporate client. By responding to these questions, the attendee gives the corporate client information about the attendee’s plans for attending that specific meeting.

If you choose to provide us with your Personally Identifiable Information, we may transfer that Personally Identifiable Information within Certain, across borders and from your country to other countries around the world. If you are subject to the European Union Data Protection Directive, laws implementing the Directive, or similar laws, you hereby freely consent to the transfer of your Personally Identifiable Information outside of the European Union to the United States and other countries and to the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by Certain as described in this Privacy Policy.

Certain, Inc. complies with the U.S. – E.U. and U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Certain, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Certain Software, Inc.’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

We do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties. We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We may also share your information under the following circumstances:

  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * If Certain, Inc. is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information
  * To establish and utilize, in conjunction with the information technology infrastructure, including data mining and other advanced analytical tools, in order to access, receive, and analyze data and information in furtherance of Certains’ business and market intelligence capabilities
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so

**Choice  
**You may choose whether or not to provide Personally Identifiable Information to Certain. If you choose not to provide the Personally Identifiable Information we request, you can still visit most of Certain's web sites, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers and services (such as Certain software) that involve our interaction with you.

When we collect your Personally Identifiable Information, we will provide a means for you to opt-out of Certain sharing your Personally Identifiable Information with our business partners. For example, should you elect to receive our Newsletter and/or promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving further communications by following those instructions in the email and/or via the unsubscribe link contained in the email. Even if you opt-out of such uses, you understand and consent to Certains’ sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information with third party payment processors, solely for the purposes of processing your payment for the Certain services. 

For attendees, if you decide to use Certain software services we will only send e-mail messages directly relating to registrations, including:

  * Confirmation of completed registration
  * Notice of incomplete registration
  * Additional information about the event or your registration

We do not allow users to elect not to receive these messages, because they are vital to completing the registration process.

The event organizer has the option of using your Personally Identifiable Information, which we provide to them, in order to send you information. Certain is not responsible for the privacy practices of event organizers who are its clients.

**Links to Other Web Sites  
**Our Site includes links to other Web sites, such as our blogs & forums, which may be facilitated by a third party. Such sites’ privacy practices may differ from those of Certain, Inc. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

**Blog / Forum**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. Our blog is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personally identifiable information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. ****

**Customer Testimonials & Reviews  
**We may post our clients’ comments, testimonials & reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their comments. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@certain.com](mailto:privacy@certain.com).

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Web site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Web site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Web site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. ****

**Single Sign-On**

You can log in to our Web site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personally identifiable information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. ****

**Security  
**The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at privacy@certain.com.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies  
**Some of our web pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about web site activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personally Identifiable Information previously indicated by a web user. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. [We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our Web site.] A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. [We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once if you so choose.] You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed.

We use Google Analytics, a third-party tracking service, which uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about our visitors to our site in the aggregate to capture usage and volume statistics. Some of our business partners (e.g., Google Analytics) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by Certain Software only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third-party.

Our use of cookies, third party cookies and other tracking technologies allows us to improve our web site and your web experience.

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences.truste.com/).  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Access / Accuracy  
**Certain is likewise committed to maintaining the accuracy of your Personally Identifiable Information. You may review your Personally Identifiable Information by sending us an email request at privacy@certain.com. Should you discover inaccuracies in your Personally Identifiable Information, or if you merely wish to update your Personally identifiable Information, you may do so by sending corrections and updates to privacy@certain.com or you may call 888-CERTAIN. You may also contact us to request that we delete your Personally Identifiable Information. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

If you decide to use Certain software services and you provide registration information for an event through our product, you receive a confirmation code. This code can be used to access or change your information at a later date by sending an e-mail with your full name and confirmation code to the event's customer service representative. This person is listed on the event's online registration form.

**We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.   We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.**

**Your Consent  
**By using this web site, you consent to the terms of our Privacy Policy and to Certains’ processing of Personally Identifiable Information for the purposes given above.

**Changes  
**We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Us  
**If you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, please email us at privacy@certain.com or contact us via post mail:

**_Certain Software, Inc. |  75 Hawthorne Street, Suite 550  |  San Francisco, CA 94105_**

Effective Date:  **06/11/2014**
